Guide to the Feminist Women's Health Center Records, 1973-2003 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Legal Files Series, 1973-1990 and undated, (6 boxes)
  - Lynn Miller, 1980 (Box 100)
  - Copies of Sprinkle letter- "Our Proposal," 1981 May 18 (Box 100)
  - Copies of Terry Sprinkle memo, 1981 Jul 8 (Box 100)
  - Rejection letter from Sprinkle, 1981 Jul 20 (Box 100)
  - Letter of proposal to change regs for second trimester (Box 100)
  - Correspondence with federal legislature, 1982 (Box 100)
  - Birth control regulations, 1982 (Box 100)
  - "Congress and the Abortion Issue," 1979-1981 (Box 100)
  - Dealing with the feds (Box 100)
  - Family Protection Act (Box 100)
  - Family Protection Act- S.1808, 1979 (Box 100)
  - Hatch Amendment (Box 100)
  - Hatch Amendment letters, 1982 (Box 100)
  - Information from Wyche Fowler, 1981 (Box 100)
  - New York legislature (Box 100)
  - Sterilization regulations, 1982 May 19 (Box 100)
  - Abortion litigation- ACLU, 1979 (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous cases- abortion litigation (Box 100)
  - Reproductive Freedom Project litigation- ACLU (Box 100)
  - ACLU Reproductive Freedom Project- legal docket (Box 100)
  - ACLU analysis of H.L.V. Matheson (Box 100)
  - Analysis of 1983 decision (Box 100)
  - Harriss v. McRae (Medicaid) Supreme Court decision, 1980 (Box 100)
  - Louisiana- APHA Amicus (Box 100)
  - McRae v. HEW- Hyde Amendment, 1980 (Box 100)
  - Planned Parenthood of Kansas City vs. Ashcroft, 1980 Jan 23 (Box 100)
  - Planned Parenthood vs. Missouri, 1980-1981 (Box 100)
  - ACLU reproductive rights packet, 1979 Oct (Box 101)
  - ACLU reproductive rights packet, 1979 Mar (Box 101)
  - Roe v. Wade Decision, 1973 Jan 22 (Box 101)
  - Bellotti v. Baird, 1979 Jul 26 (Box 101)
  - Florida clinic reg. legal brief (Box 101)
  - Mahoning Women's Center v. Hunter, et al., 1979 (Box 101)
  - Okel, McKinney, Manis proposed changes to amended rules, 1979 Nov (Box 101)
  - NAF Letters to DHR, 1979 Nov 21 (Box 101)
  - CHAMP letter to Okel, 1979 Nov 20 (Box 101)
  - Warren Hern letter to Okel, 1979 Nov 17 (Box 101)
  - HSA letter re: regulations, 1979 Oct 23 (Box 101)
  - ARM statement to Physical Health Subcommittee, 1979 Nov 21 (Box 101)
  - Statement to Physical Health FWHC Subcommittee DHR, 1979 Nov 21 (Box 101)
  - Board of Human Resources- minutes, 1982 (Box 101)
  - Board of Human Resources- agenda, 1982 (Box 101)
  - DHR report of public hearing on ASTC regs, 1979 Jul 26 (Box 101)
  - ARM testimony at public hearing, 1979 Jul 26 (Box 101)
  - CHAMP testimony at public hearing, 1979 Jul 26 (Box 101)
  - Public hearing testimony and addendum (Box 101)
  - Correspondence from DHR, 1979 Aug (Box 101)
  - DHR newsletter- abortion regulations, 1979 Jun (Box 101)
  - DHR organizational chart, 1979 Jul 7 (Box 101)
  - James Freemont testimony to public hearing, 1979 Aug 23 (Box 101)
  - Notes for public hearing statement (Box 101)
  - Lynn Thogersen's statement- Board of Human Resources, 1979 Jun 20 (Box 101)
  - State Board of Medical Examiners, 1980 Jun 25 (Box 101)
  - 1981 clinic inspection and licensure (Box 101)
  - FWHC SurgiCenter licenses, 1983 Aug (Box 101)
  - Licensure of clinical laboratories, 1983 Feb (Box 101)
  - Planned Parenthood review, 1979 (Box 101)
  - D&E regulations, 1983 (Box 101)
  - Letter to Georgia Board of Human Resources, 1979 Nov 15 (Box 101)
  - Follow-up letters after the public hearing, 1979 (Box 101)
  - Amended SurgiCenter rules and regulations, 1979 May 31 (Box 101)
  - Certificate of need- application and regulations (Box 101)
  - Revisions to amended ASTC regulations, 1979 Dec (Box 101)
  - Licensure meeting- re: extra nurse, 1980 Oct 15 (Box 101)
  - Hearing on regulations, 1980 Jul 26 (Box 101)
  - Inspection by DHR, 1980 Jul 17 (Box 101)
  - GARAL press conference, 1979 Nov 20 (Box 101)
  - GARAL annual meetings, 1979 Nov 18 (Box 101)
  - GARAL Board meeting, 1979 Nov 15 (Box 101)
  - House Subcommittee meeting, 1979 Nov 7 (Box 101)
  - Public hearing report, 1979 Jul 26 (Box 101)
  - Legislature tour of AFWHC report, 1979 Jul 11 (Box 101)
  - Meeting with Scott Sprinkle, 1979 Jul 10 (Box 101)
  - Ward Cates meeting, 1979 Jul 2 (Box 101)
  - McKinney Subcommittee, 1979 Jun 27 (Box 101)
  - Conversation with Susman, 1979 Jun 23 (Box 101)
  - Board of Human Resources, 1979 Jun 20 (Box 101)
  - Physical Health Subcommittee- Board of Human Resources, 1979 Jun 20 (Box 101)
  - Phone call with Carol Downer, 1979 Jun 13 (Box 101)
  - Portland regulations, 1980 Apr 1 (Box 101)
  - Birth center regulations, 1982-1983 (Box 101)
  - DHR abortion statistics, 1978 (Box 101)
  - Correspondence with DHR, 1984 (Box 101)
  - FWHC GARAL conference proposal, 1979 Nov 16 (Box 101)
  - Board letters, 1979 Nov 15 (Box 101)
  - Letter to Ms. McCrory, 1979 Jun 25 (Box 101)
  - Letter to McKinney Subcommittee, 1979 Jun 22 (Box 101)
  - Letter to Clinic administrator, 1979 Jun 19 (Box 101)
  - Clinic administrator letter- rough draft, 1979 Jun (Box 101)
  - Regs letter- final draft, 1979 Jun 18 (Box 101)
  - Regs letter- second draft, 1979 Jun 18 (Box 101)
  - Regs letter- first draft, 1979 Jun (Box 101)
  - Notes on reg/changes and objections for letter to DHR (Box 101)
  - McKinney Subcommittee (Box 102)
  - House of Representatives- Health and Ecology Committee (Box 102)
  - FWHC statement to House Subcommittee, 1979 Nov 7 (Box 102)
  - Correspondence from House Subcommittee, 1979 (Box 102)
  - Lynn Thogerson's statement- Subcommittee meeting, 1979 Jun 27 (Box 102)
  - Joe Burton Bill 1593, 1980 (Box 102)
  - Statements on HB300 hearing, 1981 Dec 9 (Box 102)
  - News articles, 1979 (Box 102)
  - GARAL press conference, 1979 Nov 20 (Box 102)
  - Abortion series- Atlanta Journal, 1979 Jul 8-10 (Box 102)
  - Abortion series- Constitution, 1979 Aug 20-22 (Box 102)
  - Northside abortion death press coverage, 1979 Jul (Box 102)
  - Women's Pavilion abortion complications (Box 102)
  - WIGO- editorial, 1979 Aug 16 (Box 102)
  - ARM press release, 1979 Nov 20 (Box 102)
  - Press release- public hearing, 1979 Jul 26 (Box 102)
  - Northside abortion death press statement, 1979 Jul 20 (Box 102)
  - Press statement- Subcommittee to FWHC, 1979 Jul 11 (Box 102)
  - Press statement- Subcommittee, 1979 Jun 27 (Box 102)
  - Press statement- org., 1979 Jun 20 (Box 102)
  - Abortion complications news statements, 1979 Jun (Box 102)
  - D&E regulations process, 1983 (Box 102)
  - Law and regulations (Box 102)
  - Surgicenter regulations, 1979 May 31 (Box 102)
  - Clinical lab regulations, 1979 (Box 102)
  - Chapter 26-12 abortion (Box 102)
  - Chapter 290-5-32- rules of DHR, 1979 May 3 (Box 102)
  - Code 88-1901 (Box 102)
  - Abortion articles- Supreme Court decision (Box 102)
  - Article on local vs. general- first draft (Box 102)
  - Glossary of Congressional terms (Box 102)
  - Regulations for ambulatory surgical treatment centers, 1980 Mar 1 (Box 102)
  - Rules of Georgia State Board of Pharmacology (Box 102)
  - Title XX- Georgia, 1981 (Box 102)
  - Washington state regulations, 1981 Jun 2 (Box 102)
  - California Midwife Act, 1981 (Box 102)
  - NAF standards (Box 102)
  - Day surgery services and facilities (Box 102)
  - California clinic regulations, 1979 (Box 102)
  - Work on California regulations, 1979 (Box 102)
  - Florida regulations, 1979 Jan 30 (Box 102)
  - Oregon regulations, 1980 Mar 6 (Box 103)
  - Planned Parenthood guidelines (Box 103)
  - State team reports (Box 103)
  - City government (Box 103)
  - City of Atlanta information, 1979 (Box 103)
  - Legislation/lobbying/reproductive rights, (2 folders) (Box 103)
- Closed Series, 1973-2003, (22 boxes)
  Contains materials sensitive in nature that have been removed from other series in the collection.
  CLOSED: All materials in this series are currently CLOSED to research.
  - Materials closed to research (Box 104-125)
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1989, 1992, and undated, (2 boxes)
  Consists of 28 audiocassettes and 11 videocassettes. Audiocassettes are primarily recordings of workshops, conference sessions, and events. Videocassettes are primarily educational. One videocassette documents anti-abortion protesters outside the FWHC.
  RESTRICTION: Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use copies will need to be created before items can be accessed by researchers. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use these audiovisual materials.
  - Audiocassettes, 1992, (28 items)
    - Audiocassettes, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-001 "Anti's on Your Doorstep: Life After Bray," Lynne Randall, Elaine Metlin, and Helen Neuborne, San Diego California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-002 Annual membership luncheon: Tietze and Burdick Awards and President's address, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-003 "Better Safe Than Sorry: Clinic regulation update," Adele Hughey, Deborah Kelly, and Jeri Camara, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-004 "Clinic Support Workshop: The Bottom Line Principles in Practice A," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-005 "Clinic Support Workshop: The Bottom Line Principles in Practice B," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-006 "Clinic Support Workshop: The Bottom Line Principles in Practice C," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-007 "Clinic Support Workshop: The Bottom Line Principles in Practice D," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-008 "Closing Session: Cooperation and Competition," Francis Kissling, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-009 "The Cultural Divide: Effectively Managing Diversity," Suzzane Poppema and Donna Stringer, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-010 "The Cultural Divide: Effectively Managing Diversity," Suzzane Poppema and Donna Stringer, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-011 "Empowering Doctors: Combating Terrorist Tactics," Elizabeth Karlin, Ralph Bundy, Elaine Metlin, George Tiller, and Susan Wicklund, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-012 "General Session: Choice '92: Abortion in the Political Landscape," James Wagner, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-013 "General Session: Welcome to California by Congresswoman Barbara Boxer (D-CA) and Déjà vu All Over Again: Before and After Roe," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-014 "The Great Debate, IUD vs. Norplant," Michael Burnhill, Jacqueline Darroch Forrest and Maria Lacarra, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-015 "High Risk Teens: Responsible Intervention," Wayne Pawlowski, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-016 "Insight for Insiders: Legal and Legislative Update," Diane Pollack, Marcy Bloom, Joanne Blum, and Robin Rothrock, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-017 "Post Graduate Seminar: Post Abortion Complications and Their Management A," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-018 "Post Graduate Seminar: Post Abortion Complications and Their Management B," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-019 "Post Graduate Seminar: Post Abortion Complications and Their Management C," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-020 "Post Graduate Seminar: Post Abortion Complications and Their Management D," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-021 "Pre-Abortion Care; Counseling and Informed Consent," Jeannine Michael, Carolyn Buhl, Genevieve Grein, and Anita Wilson (Box 126)
    - OR-022 "Scientific Papers A," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-023 "Scientific Papers B," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-024 "Scientific Papers C," San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-025 "Second Trimester Abortion: Attitudes and Responses," Terry Beresford, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-026 "Successful Strategies: Managing the Media," Peggy Jarman and Kathy Bonk, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-027 "Warren's World: Explorations in the Upper Pisque River of the Peruvian Amazon," W. Hern, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
    - OR-028 "Who Will Provide Abortions? Practitioner Shortage Update," Pat Anderson, Rachel Atkins, Trent MacKay, and Michael Policar, San Diego, California, 1992 (Box 126)
  - Videocassettes, 1989 and undated, (11 items)
    - Videocassettes, 1989 and undated (Box 127)
    - OR-029 "Early Options: A Providers Guide to Medical Abortion" (Box 127)
    - OR-030 "Fetal Indication Termination of Pregnancy Program" (Box 127)
    - OR-031 News Coverage- Abortion Protests FWHC, 1989 Mar 15 (Box 127)
    - OR-032 "Norplant System: Insertion/Removal Techniques" (Box 127)
    - OR-033 "Norplant System: Counseling- The Key to Patient Acceptance" (Box 127)
    - OR-034 "Norplant System: Removal Technique" (Box 127)
    - OR-035 "Obstetrics and Gynecology: The Pill" (Box 127)
    - OR-036 "Obstetrics and Gynecology: Sexually Transmitted Diseases" (Box 127)
    - OR-037 "Obstetrics and Gynecology: Vaginal Infections" (Box 127)
    - OR-038 "Su Derecho a Elegir: Guia para la Mujer Sobre el Aborto Medico" (Box 127)
    - OR-039 Sunday (2) (Box 127)